The AI nightmare scenario has arrived
for actors. Young performers are getting
booked for roles in short dramas only to
find out they've been replaced by AI
shortly [music] before filming begins.
Short dramas, also called verticals or
micro dramas, have been rapidly gaining
popularity in the US over the [music]
past couple years. These short soap
opera style series became a billion
dollar industry in the country last
year.
>> [music]
>> They've become an important source of
income for Los Angeles actors as other
opportunities dry up. But lately studios
have been looking for ways to cut
[music] costs using AI. An AI generated
micro drama can cost a few thousand
dollars to produce, whereas filming with
[music] human actors can cost hundreds
of thousands of dollars. Actors like
Blake [music] Manning, Hannah Lowry, and
Luke Dodge told me they've seen AI
creeping into their work this year. Some
have lost jobs to AI, while others
[music] said they've been told to
approve synthetic versions of themselves
in scenes. This matters. Micro dramas
could be a canary [music] in the coal
mine for Hollywood. If studio executives
turn to AI to cut costs, it could have
sweeping ramifications for [music]
professional actors and the industry at
large. You can read more about what's
happening in my new story with Lucia
Moses [music]
on Business Insider.